Chris: When working in ‘Agile’
development you will constantly hear the
terms ‘backlog’, ‘Epics’, ‘Features’,
‘Themes’ and ‘User Stories’, so
what do these different terms mean?
Leah: Let’s first take a look at backlogs.
There are two types of backlogs,
product backlogs and sprint backlogs.
Chris: Product backlogs contain
the list of work items that need
to be completed for the project.
Items are ranked in order of
importance, so that the team knows
which items need to be completed first.
Simply put, the ‘product backlog’ is
like a ‘To-Do list’ of tasks, that
helps to drive progress and keeps the
development always moving forward.
When there is capacity, members of
the team move items from the ‘product
backlog’ into the ‘sprint backlog’.
A good thing to note is that the
‘product backlog’ is not set in stone,
when working in ‘Agile’, projects are
constantly evolving and the ‘product
backlog’ is changed to reflect this.
Leah: So, what about the sprint backlog?
The ‘sprint backlog’ is where
the items taken from the
‘product backlog’ are placed.
Once in the ‘sprint backlog’, the items
are included in the current sprint, and
must be completed by the ‘scrum team’.
This may be over a period of 1, 2, 3 or
more weeks but for software development
projects only, it is typically 2 weeks.
Unlike the ‘product backlog’ items in
the ‘sprint backlog’ can’t be changed
during the sprint, any items that are not
fully completed in the current sprint,
will carry over into the next sprint.
Chris: So, what about Epics,
User stories and Features?
All three of these terms are integral to
each other, so let’s look at Epics first.
Epics are large tasks that may need
several sprints to complete and
will contain the ‘what’s and why’.
For example, you could be asked to create
a shopping cart for an online store.
If you remember back to our first video
in session 2 when we talked about the
process of ‘requirements elicitation’, you
will begin with gathering the high-level
requirements for the project [Epics] which
will then be broken down and refined into
more detailed requirements [User Stories].
There will be several elements to
this, that can then be broken down
into smaller chunks called stories.
Leah: So, what are Stories?
Stories are small chunks of work written
in non-technical language and will give
a simple overview of what is expected.
Stories should be a complete narrative,
and provide a tangible user benefit
end to end, whilst also small
enough to complete in one sprint.
Looking at our previous
example, the online shopping
cart is classed as an ‘Epic’.
A ‘User Story’ relating to this could
be selecting the payment method.
As you can see this is a ‘subtask’
of the creation of the shopping cart.
Chris: And Features what are these?
If we look at the shopping cart
again, we have identified one of
the User Stories as the customer
wanting to select payment options.
A ‘feature’ in this instance describes
a specific solution to this requirement.
So, in our example a ‘feature’
could be a drop-down selector that
offers different payment options.
Another Feature may be another
drop down option for selecting
different postal rates.
Leah: So, what does the
term Themes relate to?
So far, we have talked about
Backlogs, Epics, User Stories
and features but what is a Theme?
When working on a project there will
be Epics and or User Stories that
share common characteristics, these
can be grouped together as a Theme.
In the examples we have been using
this ‘theme’ would relate to E-commerce
functionality and personalisation.
Chris: As you can see there are many
terms that are used when working
on ‘Agile’ projects and it can take
some time to fully understand them.
Don’t worry, as you become more
comfortable with Agile development,
understanding, and using these terms
will become very familiar to you.